<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects-relateds on Haidlir&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://haidlir.github.io/blog/projects-related/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects-relateds on Haidlir&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haidlir.github.io/blog/projects-related/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Drox SDN Application - HowTo</title>
      <link>http://haidlir.github.io/blog/projects-related/drox-HowTo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haidlir.github.io/blog/projects-related/drox-HowTo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drox is a &lt;em&gt;software defined networking&lt;/em&gt; (SDN) application built on pox controller. It is expected to control unicast traffic on flat L2 ethernet network with arbitrary topology. It uses multipath routing for the forwarding decision of each flow, hence it doesn&amp;rsquo;t transform the topology into a spanning tree or loop/circuit-free topology. A flow is combination of source-destination IP address and source-destination TCP/UDP port in the packet&amp;rsquo;s header. Packets associated in a flow are forwarded in a same path, where path is a sequence of switch/datapath between source and destination node. This application is created refering to &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enabling Mutlipath Routing for Unicast Traffic in Ethernet Network&amp;rdquo; paper&lt;/a&gt;. The rest of the artice will explain how to use &lt;em&gt;drox&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since drox is built on pox controller, you should install/copy/clone pox controller into your machine. You can find pox&amp;rsquo;s repository with all its documentations in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/noxrepo/pox&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Once your pox is working, you can download/clone/copy drox repository and place it into the &lt;em&gt;ext&lt;/em&gt; directory inside the &lt;em&gt;pox&lt;/em&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [pox-directory]/ext
git clone http://www.github.com/haidlir/drox/drox.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run drox sdn application, just execute &lt;em&gt;run.sh&lt;/em&gt;. That shell script (&lt;em&gt;run.sh&lt;/em&gt;) makes &lt;em&gt;pox.py&lt;/em&gt; to call &lt;em&gt;main.py&lt;/em&gt; (in drox directory) and the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd drox
chmod +x run.sh
./run.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since drox also provides Dynamic Host Control Protocol (DHCP) server, all end-hosts in the topology which handled by drox, should be configured to use dynamic ip address. For convenient, you can use &lt;em&gt;Mininet&lt;/em&gt;, a network simulator complemented with &lt;em&gt;Open vSwitch&lt;/em&gt;, so you can connect all switches to controller (drox). You can download the mininet topology script &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/haidlir/mn-script/master/abilene/abilene.py&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for example. You can also find information about mininet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mininet.org&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before run the topology, make sure that you have change the controller ip address, that mininet refers to, into the appropriate ip address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
    net = Mininet(Abilene(), switch=OVSKernelSwitch, controller=None)
    net.addController(RemoteController( name=&#39;c0&#39;, ip=&#39;[controller&#39;s ip address]&#39; ))
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, run the topology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo python abilene.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>